Guide to the Foggy Bottom Association records, 1969-2006 MS2311
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Foggy Bottom Association records
1969-2006
1980-2006
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Foggy Bottom Association
MS2311
4.75 Linear Feet 9 document boxes, one map folder
This collection contains Foggy Bottom Association records related to historic preservation and urban renewal in the Foggy Bottom neighborhood. The association has been very active in advocating for the preservation of the residential character of Foggy Bottom as profound changes have come to the neighborhood since the mid-20th century.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains Foggy Bottom Association records related to historic preservation and urban renewal in the Foggy Bottom neighborhood. The association has been very active in advocating for the preservation of the residential character of Foggy Bottom as profound changes have come to the neighborhood since the mid-20th century.
Files include meeting minutes and administrative files as well as memoranda and correspondence with various public officials, including Advisory Neighborhood Commission representatives, mayors, DC Council members, and the president of The George Washington University. They also include historical and architectural studies of many addresses and landmark buildings in the neighborhood, and reports and proposals for new or modified buildings and open spaces. While the files date primarily from the 1980s-2000s, the information gathered within them also offers insight into the neighborhood's 19th and early 20th century character.
Biographical / Historical
The Foggy Bottom Association was formed by a group of citizens in 1955 and was formally incorporated in the District of Columbia on June 19, 1959, as the Foggy Bottom Restoration Association. The present name was formally adopted and ratified May 13, 1965. It was founded to enhance and protect the residential quality of the area and keep residents informed on matters affecting the community. The objectives of the FBA are to further the civic, cultural, social and economic welfare of the Foggy Bottom/West End community; preserve and enhance the residential character of the community; and promote historic preservation in the area.
Information on the Foggy Bottom Association taken from http://www.foggybottomassociation.com.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Foggy Bottom Association, 2012 (2012.077)
Foggy Bottom (Washington, D.C.); Historic preservation; Neighborhood planning -- United States -- Citizen participation.; Foggy Bottom Association
- 26th and K PUD (The Griffin), 1983 February 28-1984 September 7 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 26th and K Tunnel, 1985 April 8-1985 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 26th and L PUD - Egyptian Defense Ministry, 1987 April - 1987 May (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 26th Street Park, 1999 December 5 - 2001 October 24 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 27th and K Parkland, 1999 October 26 - 2002 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 902 New Hampshire Avenue NW, 1999 January 24 - 1999 May 9 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 912 25th Street, 2008 February 22 - 2008 July 23 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 912 New Hampshire 7-11, 1992 December 9 - 1997 October 6 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 935 26th Street, 2003 June (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 935 26th Street, 2003 August 12 - 2004 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- 947 25th Street, 2005 June 13 - 2005 August 5 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 1957 E Street, 2002 March 18 - 2002 November 12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 2407-2409 I Street, 2002 December 12 - 2003 January 16 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 2417 I Street, 1990 June 27 - 1990 July 13 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 2425 I Street, 2001 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- 2425 L Street (Columbia Hospital), 2003 September 12 - 2003 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- 2501 Pennsylvania Avenue, 2004 December 15 - 2005 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- 2512 I Street, 2004 February 13 - 2005 March 16 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- 2516 I Street, 1998 January 20 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- 2517 PA [Pennsylvania Avenue], 1999 - 2001 September 17 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- 2520 I Street, 2002 January 23 - 2003 January 16 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- 2530 I [Street], 1989 September 19 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- CHW 2425 L [Columbia Hospital for Women, 1 of 4], 2002 July - 2005 August 25 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- CHW 2425 L [Columbia Hospital for Women, 2 of 4], 2003 February 10 - 2003 July 18 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- CHW 2425 L [Columbia Hospital for Women, 3 of 4], 1914 January 23 - 2003 July 16 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- CHW 2425 L [Columbia Hospital for Women, 4 of 4], 1923 February 11 - 2003 February 11 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Circle Theatre, 1969 March 16 - 1996 May 14 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Columbia Hospital [1 of 2], 1986 December 16 - 2003 November 20 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Columbia Hospital [2 of 2], 2003 February 28 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- FBHDC Incorporation, 1989 August 9 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Comprehensive Plan [1 of 3], 1996 July 7 - 1999 February 19 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Comprehensive Plan [2 of 3], 1992 September 29 - 1997 June 17 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Comprehensive Plan [3 of 3], 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Conservancy - 917 25th, 1998 June 1 - 1998 June 13 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Conservancy/FB Issues, 1978 March 7 - 2000 September 30 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Conservancy: GW Hospital Issue, 1998 August 6 - 1999 January 5 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Conservancy: Membership/Lists, 1990 March 16 - 2007 April (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Conservancy: Minutes/Agenda, 1989 May 18 - 2005 February 25 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Cooper Houses, 1989 May 12 - 1992 January 30 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- DC Council Letters Gen., 1990 April 10 - 2006 February 16 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- FB [Foggy Bottom] Historic District [1 of 2], 1983 January - 1991 May 17 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- FB [Foggy Bottom] Historic District [2 of 2], 1982 August - 1987 June 18 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- FBHDC Bylaws, 1989 June 28 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- General Traffic/Transportation Info, 1979 August - 1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- General Zoning Material, 1977 February - 1997 May (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Grant School, 2006 December 21 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Grant School, 2002 April 10 - 2006 May 25 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- GW - Student Behavior [1 of 2], 1992 August - 2005 April 11 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- GW - Student Behavior [2 of 2], 1991 May 4 - 2003 April 28 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- G.W. University Inn, 1992 April 27 - 1998 September 28 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Historic District Overlay, 1992 April 17 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Historic District Zoning, 1987 June 18 - 1991 October 28 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Historic Preservation [1 of 2], 1987 June 18 - 2000 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Historic Preservation [2 of 2], 1989 September - 1993 May (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Historic Preservation Conservancy, 1983 November - 2007 April (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Hughes Mews 2004, 2004 February 26 - 2004 May 24 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Hughes Mews 2513 I Rear, 2001 June 21 - 2001 August 30 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Juarez Circle, 2006 May 11 - 2007 September (Box 6, Folder 1)
- K St. Park, 2001 July 18 - 2001 December 13 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- KC [Kennedy Center] Traffic, 2002 March 15 - 2002 August 22 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Kennedy Center, 1998 July - 2005 November 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Lower West End Study [1 of 3], 2006 September 10 - 2008 February 8 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Lower West End Study [2 of 3], 2006 July (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Lower West End Study [3 of 3], 2006 July (Box 6, Folder 7)
- National Trust for Historic Preservation, 2000 June 3 - 2002 January 9 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- NPS Register of Historic Places - FB [Foggy Bottom], 1987 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Office of Planning, 2001 June 7 - 2002 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- River Inn 924 25th [St.], 1996 January 6 - 2002 May 7 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Rock Creek and Potomac Parkway, 2005 May (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Signs for FB [Foggy Bottom], 1999 August 31 - 2002 August 12 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Snows Court - Hughes Mews Repaving, 1996 June 17 - 2002 January 24 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Square 14 - Luzon, etc. 25th and Penn [1 of 3], 1991 August - 1992 January 29 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Square 14 - Luzon, etc. 25th and Penn [2 of 3], 1990 October 25 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Square 14 - Luzon, etc. 25th and Penn [3 of 3], 1987 September 7 - 1992 February (Box 7, Folder 3)
- St. Paul's, 1996 May 1 - 2004 September 30 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- St. Paul's Church K St., 1999 June - 2001 April 10 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Tax Exempt Properties [1 of 2], 2000 August 4 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Tax Exempt Properties [2 of 2], 2000 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Third Church of Christ Scientist, 2003 March 12 - 2005 July 23 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- TR [Theodore Roosevelt] Bridge Task Group [1 of 3], 2004 April 7 - 2007 March 8 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- TR [Theodore Roosevelt] Bridge Task Group [2 of 3], 2003 December 2 - 2004 March 3 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- TR [Theodore Roosevelt] Bridge Task Group [3 of 3], 1999 September 3 - 2003 November 13 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Traceries - Archit. Study of FB [Foggy Bottom], 1981 October 19 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Triangle Park NH [New Hampshire] Ave., 2001 February 20 - 2002 October 22 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- US News and World Report Bldg. [1 of 3], 1987 September 1 - 1988 June 20 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- US News and World Report Bldg. [2 of 3], 1987 January 30 - 1987 July 16 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- US News and World Report Bldg. [3 of 3], undated (Map-folder 1)
- West End Apartments [1 of 2], 1981 September 30 - 1992 June 3 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- West End Apartments [2 of 2], 1988 September 29 - 1992 July 6 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Whitehurst Freeway 1981-85 and 1993 [1 of 3], 1981 - 1983 July 8 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Whitehurst Freeway 1981-85 and 1993 [2 of 3], 1982 September 15 - 1983 December 1 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Whitehurst Freeway 1981-85 and 1993 [3 of 3], 1984 January 17 - 1993 September 8 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Whitehurst Freeway, 2003-2007 [1 of 2], 2005 March - 2007 July 4 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Whitehurst Freeway, 2003-2007 [2 of 2], 2005 (Box 9, Folder 5)